Nyamumbe Brian Isaboke

Information Technology Specialist

22/12/1997

≥ nyamumbebrian157@gmail.com

+254727903007 • Nairobi, Kenya

in linkedin.com/in/brian-nyamumbe

★ https://brianprofile.netlify.app/

Profile

I am a passionate IT support specialist, web developer and graphic designer with 1 year experience as an IT specialist. Having great skills in full stack web development; Javascript, Node.js, React, among other skills I aspire to work with developers and clients to make organizations reach their peak in technology. Having in-depth understanding of diverse computer systems and networks, I am excellent in the technical aspects of IT technology thus providing support to users and making me the first point of contact for error reporting.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Technlogy, *University of Eldoret* 2018 – 2022 | Eldoret, Kenya

Certificate of Proficiency in Computer Applications, Kenya Institute of Management 04/2018 – 05/2018 | Nanyuki, Kenya

Goethe German Zertifikat A2,

Goethe Institut-Muenchen
06/2016 – 07/2016 | Munich, Germany

Skills

Technical aspects of IT Technology

Used computers, software and networks to organize data and information thus spent less time correcting mistakes and searching for information. Provided support to users therefore, I was the first point of contact for error reporting. Installing and configuring hardware and software components to ensure usability.

Microsoft Office Suite

(Developed new and complex Excel sheets to generate ICT equipment issuance data quickly reducing time from 14 days to 7).

(Used Microsoft Word to make different formats in accordance with the need and importance thus enabled users to integrate Microsoft Word with Excel tables to create a spreadsheet and display on the required document for efficient presentation of information).

(Used Microsoft Teams to combine workplace chat, meetings, notes, and attachments thus enabled collaboration and communication between the users).

Web Development

I am skilled to work with the following frontend and backend web development languages; HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.JS and React in designing responsive websites in accordance with the changing technology of Web Development applications.

Graphic Design

Proficient in using Adobe Photoshop 2021. In designing I use the aesthetics of typography and the compositional arrangement of the text, ornamentation, and imagery to convey ideas, feelings, and attitudes beyond what language alone expresses.

Great Communication Skills

Built good and lasting relationship with all my colleagues and senior management and ensured there were systems and resources in place to deal with any of their queries in less than 10 hours.

Professional Experience

Web Developer and Graphics Designer,

Freelancing

2021 - present | Nairobi, Kenya

I am working as a freelancer, designing responsive websites and graphics design in accordance with the changing technology of Web Development applications.

Information Technology Intern,

Eldoret Law Courts

05/2022 - 07/2022 | Eldoret, Kenya

I served as an IT Intern under the ICT Department. During this period, I gained practical skills and hands-on experience in the following areas:

- Providing user support on the use of computer hardware and software applications.
- Installing and upgrading computer software and hardware components to ensure usability.
- PC hardware maintenance and troubleshooting techniques to solve software issues and replace damaged hardware.
- Computer networking and configuration to support traffic, improve network security, and increase network stability.
- Installing and upgrading anti-virus software to ensure security at the user level.

Hotel Steward, Kongoni Camp Hotel

04/2019 - 08/2019 | Nanyuki, Kenya

While working in the Hospitality Industry, I gained experience in offering good customer service and discussing any issues with a wide variety of individuals and groups. I am equipped with social media management skills which entails creating and publishing content, interacting with users, and analyzing performance.

References

Wycliffe Ireri, *ICT Officer*, Eldoret Law Courts wyckieireri@gmail.com, +254703603017

Isabella Karani, *Teacher*, Inoro Secondary School isabkieb@yahoo.com., +254723549719

Cyrus Maina, *German Teacher*, Inoro Secondary School wairagu24@gmail.com, +254722452971